Of all the creatures on the planet, the narwhal is one of the strangest looking.
在地球上所有的生物中，独角鲸是长相最奇特的物种之一。
It's a whale which has a large protruding tusk coming out of its head; that's how it got its nickname, the unicorn of the sea.
它是一种鲸鱼，头部伸出一根巨大的突出长牙；这就是它绰号"海洋独角兽"的由来。
They live in the Arctic Ocean off the coast of Canada, Russia and East Greenland.
它们生活在加拿大、俄罗斯和东格陵兰沿岸的北冰洋海域。
However, experts say some populations of narwhal could be extinct by 2025, and it's all because of noise pollution.
然而，专家表示，到2025年，一些独角鲸种群可能会灭绝，而这一切都是因为噪声污染。
Narwhals rely on echolocation, which they use to find food and navigate their surroundings.
独角鲸依靠回声定位来寻找食物和航行于周围环境。
The animal produces a sound wave which bounces off an object.
这种动物发出声波，声波碰到物体后反弹。
They pick this reflected sound up through their lower jaw, and information on features like size and speed passes to their ears.
它们通过下颌接收反射回来的声音，有关物体大小和速度等信息会传递到它们的耳朵。
However, increase in human marine activity, as well as climate change, has resulted in the Arctic Ocean becoming noisier, which means it's more difficult for narwhals to rely on sound.
然而，人类海洋活动的增加以及气候变化，导致北冰洋变得更加嘈杂，这意味着独角鲸更难依靠声音。
Susanna Blackwell, who studies the effects of underwater noise on marine animals, told the BBC that there is noisier activity in the Arctic Ocean than ever because, as sea ice melts, new navigation routes are opening.
研究水下噪声对海洋动物影响的苏珊娜·布莱克威尔告诉BBC，北冰洋的嘈杂活动比以往任何时候都多，因为随着海冰融化，新的航行路线正在开辟。
And while icebergs breaking and creaking have been part of the ocean soundscape for hundreds of years, man-made noise is much harder for animals to adapt to, particularly as these changes are so sudden.
虽然冰山断裂和嘎吱作响的声音几百年来一直是海洋声景的一部分，但人造噪声对动物来说更难适应，尤其是这些变化如此突然。
Research published in Science Advances in 2023 recorded the reactions of narwhals to the simulated noises of oil expeditions made by a patrol vessel.
2023年发表在《科学进展》上的研究记录了独角鲸对一艘巡逻船发出的模拟石油勘探噪声的反应。
The scientists tagged and tracked the creatures and found that, on hearing these sounds, they ended deep dives and stopped clicking, the echolocation signal they use for finding food underwater.
科学家们对它们进行标记和跟踪，发现听到这些声音后，它们会结束深潜并停止发出咔哒声——这是它们用来在水下寻找食物的回声定位信号。
This is the same reaction narwhals have to orcas, who hunt them, meaning human-made noise could trigger the creature's 'threat button'.
这与独角鲸面对捕食者虎鲸时的反应相同，意味着人造噪声可能触发这种生物的"威胁按钮"。
So, what can we do?
那么，我们能做些什么呢？
Charlotte Findlay, a postdoctoral fellow at Aarhus University, says "noise is actually quite easy to solve.
奥胡斯大学的博士后研究员夏洛特·芬德利说："噪声实际上很容易解决。
We need to either turn it off or turn it down."
我们要么关掉它，要么调低它。"